<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>til on chekos' today i learned</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/</link><description>Recent content in til on chekos' today i learned</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright © 2022, chekos.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 16:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://til.chekos.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using GitHub Actions to produce example images of code</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/2022/08/14/using-github-actions-to-produce-example-images-of-code/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://til.chekos.dev/2022/08/14/using-github-actions-to-produce-example-images-of-code/</guid><description>what i learned I learned to chain a lot of small tools using GitHub Actions to produce ready-to-share images of code examples for social media (namely, instagram and twitter) from my phone. The steps, generally speaking, go as follows:
Create a new page on a Notion Database. Probably will create a specific template for this, like I do with TIL’s but it’s not necessary. GitHub Action: Use my markdownify-notion python package to write the markdown version of this page and save it on a “quarto project” folder.</description></item><item><title>how to solve permission error from airflow official docker image</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/2022/01/27/how-to-solve-permission-error-from-airflow-official-docker-image/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://til.chekos.dev/2022/01/27/how-to-solve-permission-error-from-airflow-official-docker-image/</guid><description>what i learned tl;dr: when you use the Airflow official docker image you need to make sure that the variable AIRFLOW_UID is set to match your UID (and AIRFLOW_GID=0 aka root ) or you’re going to get permission errors. i was working on deploying Airflow on a VM at work this week and I got a permission error (Errno 13) regarding the containers’ python’s logging config. When I first started working with this docker-compose.</description></item><item><title>jq [] syntax</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/2022/01/25/jq-syntax/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://til.chekos.dev/2022/01/25/jq-syntax/</guid><description>what i learned If you want to dump a list of objects you’re constructing from some other json you need to wrap your entire jq string in square brackets ( [] ). Otherwise you’ll be writing each object one at a time and that’s not valid JSON. For example, running something like
jq &amp;#39;.[] | {id: .id, title: .title, created: .created } returns →
{ id: &amp;#34;123&amp;#34;, title: &amp;#34;page 1&amp;#34;, created: &amp;#34;2022-01-25T23:15:00.</description></item><item><title>how to execute a shell script in the current shell</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/2021/09/09/how-to-execute-a-shell-script-in-the-current-shell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://til.chekos.dev/2021/09/09/how-to-execute-a-shell-script-in-the-current-shell/</guid><description>what i learned when you execute a shell script, it defaults to creating a new shell, executing the script in that shell and closing it. if you want to, for example, set environmental variables you would need to run the script in the current shell. let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to have a short shell script that sets the database url as an environmental variable called env_vars.sh.
#!/bin/bash export DATABASE_URL=&amp;#34;super_secret_url&amp;#34; if you run</description></item><item><title>how to delete tags on remote repos</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/06/23/how-to-delete-tags-on-remote-repos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/06/23/how-to-delete-tags-on-remote-repos/</guid><description>what i learned you can delete remote tags from your github repository using git push --delete origin &amp;lt;TAG NAME&amp;gt; or you can delete locally and then push those changes to your remote repo
git tag -d 0.0.7 git push origin :refs/tag/0.0.7 how i learned recently someone became the very first contributor to pypums and when i merged their contribution and tried to automatically build and publish the package to PyPI i found myself making an error.</description></item><item><title>about MyST-parser, es markdown pero rST</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/06/22/about-myst-parser-es-markdown-pero-rst/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/06/22/about-myst-parser-es-markdown-pero-rst/</guid><description>what i learned MyST-parser is so easy to use and it provides all the functionality i need to make docs without using rST.
how i learned i was creating the docs for tacosdedatos-utils and i rather not touch rST ever. i had seen @choldraf tweet about MyST before but i had not had the need to use it.
today i made the documentation for that small utils package and it was actually a pleasant experience?</description></item><item><title>escaping liquid tags with {% raw %}</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/06/18/escaping-liquid-tags-with-raw/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/06/18/escaping-liquid-tags-with-raw/</guid><description>what i learned you can use the tags raw and endraw to escape liquid tags.
how i learned in the previous TIL i tried to write the following
{% raw %} i am moving soyserg.io from a hugo site to jekyll and i couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to have nested {{}} as in {{ category/{{category | downcase }} | relative_url }} which just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. so i moved to {{ 'category/' | append: category | downcase | relative_url }} {% endraw %}</description></item><item><title>about liquid tags</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/06/15/about-liquid-tags/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/06/15/about-liquid-tags/</guid><description>what i learned shopify has a github pages site documenting liquid tags which is very useful and easy to use.
how i learned {% raw %} i am moving soyserg.io from a hugo site to jekyll and i couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to have nested {{}} as in {{ category/{{category | downcase }} | relative_url }} which just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. so i moved to {{ 'category/' | append: category | downcase | relative_url }} {% endraw %}</description></item><item><title>about jekyll-archives</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/05/22/about-jekyll-archives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/05/22/about-jekyll-archives/</guid><description>what i learned there&amp;rsquo;s a jekyll-plugin named jekyll-archives that lets you create archives of your posts based on metadata/front matter.
i used it for socialtech.us to create a category/${category} page for each of the categories in the site (created dynamically).
how i learned the social tech collaborative website has a /categories/ page where each category has a header so you can get to each category via url like socialtech.us/categories#${category}. for example, you could go to socialtech.</description></item><item><title>you can't use special characters in unix commands if you use single-quotes</title><link>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/05/08/you-cant-use-special-characters-in-unix-commands-if-you-use-single-quotes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://til.chekos.dev/2020/05/08/you-cant-use-special-characters-in-unix-commands-if-you-use-single-quotes/</guid><description>what i learned You can&amp;rsquo;t insert variables in Unix commands if you&amp;rsquo;re using single quotes.
this won&amp;rsquo;t work
export SECRET=&amp;#34;huh&amp;#34; echo &amp;#39;you can not see my secret $SECRET&amp;#39; but this will
export SECRET=&amp;#34;huh&amp;#34; echo &amp;#34;you can see my secret $SECRET&amp;#34; how i learned while setting up a GitHub action for the social tech collaborative website that would send a url to a specific slack channel, i would get $TARGET_URL instead of the actual url.</description></item></channel></rss>